Deep in the center of our galaxy, a mysterious cluster of stars is defying explanation.
They zip around a supermassive black hole at incredible speeds, reaching nearly 10% the speed of light.
It's surprising to find any stars here at all, as the black hole shreds apart the gas clouds they're born from.
So these stars must be older ones that came here from elsewhere.
But here's the mystery.
They appear much younger than expected, as if they've found a way to cheat death.
A new theory proposes a mind-bending explanation that could rewrite our understanding of stellar evolution.
These stars could be feeding off dark matter, powered indefinitely by the most mysterious substance in the universe.
The nature of dark matter remains a total mystery.
Despite making up 85% of all material in the universe, it's completely invisible to light, and only interacts with visible matter through its gravitational effects.
It holds galaxies together like glue, and provides a kind of scaffolding for the entire universe.
Studying dark matter is next to impossible.
But some theories predict that just like matter and antimatter, dark matter particles may annihilate each other when they collide.
In the process, energy and other particles like photons may be released, which could become a source of power.
These collisions would probably only occur where dark matter is most dense, which happens to be right where those mysterious stars live, at the very center of our galaxy.
As these youthful stars zip around the galactic core, they sail through ultra-dense clouds of dark matter, sucking in dark particles, and potentially triggering collisions inside.
These collisions could be acting as an extra energy source within the stars, making them appear mysteriously young.
Immortal suns feeding off a cosmic fountain of youth.
If this is the case, it would open a whole new pathway for the life cycle of stars.
The Milky Way's core emits a strange, unexplained glow that was discovered in 2009.
Some believe that dark matter annihilation could be causing the excess radiation.
And strange, puffy G-objects have also been found near the galaxy's core.
They appear like stars surrounded by clouds of gas, but it may be that their outer layers have been puffed out by dark matter collisions inside.
In theory, some of these dark particles may be comprised of a variety of different particles, obeying their own unique chemistry.
In theory, some of these dark particles could even organize into forms of dark life.
Dark matter beings may be surrounding us right now.
Perhaps they could even be sending signals through dark matter collisions.
Messages from a shadow world.
It may still be that dark matter does not exist at all, and the anomalies we see are explained by something else.
But by studying the immortal stars at our galaxy's core, we may begin to uncover the secrets of the shadow world,
and glimpse a piece of the universe that light has never touched.
In theory, some of these dark particles could even organize into forms of light that light does not exist at all,
and the anomalies we see are explained by something else.
Thank you for watching.